Nadine Juraschek Full Stack Web Developer

nadine.jura@online.de | +49 157 36205555 | Böblingen, Germany LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nadinejuraschek Github: https://github.com/nadinejuraschek Portfolio: https://nadinejuraschek.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer looking to leverage a degree and 8 years of experience in Education with a passion for modern technology and development. As a former tech-savvy Teacher and Youth Leader, it is my goal to create and ensure access to motivational and applicable online applications for users of every background, gender, and zip code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: HTML, CSS (Grid & Flexbox), React Native, Bootstrap, Bulma, styled-components,

Semantic UI, JavaScript, jQuery, Media Queries

Back-End: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, APIs, JSON, REST, GIT, Command Line,

Programming Logic

PROJECTS

Moodsphere

A Mental Health Tracker which lets users log their daily emotional state, as well as offers resources, inspiration, and emergency hotlines.

- Led a team of 4 to complete the project on time and within specifications
- Held bi-weekly scrum meetings to ensure team communication, task and time management
- Gained experience with agile development and code reviews
- Architected frontend using Semantic UI and EJS, backend using Node.js, Express, and MongoDB
- https://moodsphere.herokuapp.com/

TeachersPET – Plan, Educate, Track

A Class Management Tool for all educators. Secure individual student data, assignments, and lesson plans can be added, deleted, and displayed for each class.

- Efficiently worked with 4 team members in a fast-paced and ever-evolving environment
- Presented and demonstrated project developments to instructors and colleagues
- Designed utilizing frontend frameworks (Bootstrap, EJS) and JavaScript libraries (Node.js, Express), as well as a relational database (MySQL and Sequelize)
- https://teacherspet-plan-educate-track.herokuapp.com/

On Par

An application to improve communication and support between Au Pairs, Host Family Members, and Community Counselors.

- Translated Au Pairs' and their agencies' needs into technical requirements
- Broke down a large project into manageable tasks
- Wrote clean readable code in JavaScript
- Continually updated the app with an interest in improving the user experience
- Architected using modern JavaScript libraries (React.js, Node.js, Express) and a NoSQL database (MongoDB)
- https://au-pair-application.herokuapp.com/

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

June 2020 – Present

Kinedu

- Maintaining a large codebase by documenting and correcting unexpected issues and bugs
- Using modern frameworks and practices (React.js, Context API, Hooks, and CSS Grid)

- Using Bitbucket, Github, Slack, Airtable, and Click Up to manage, review, and schedule tasks
- Creating landing pages for maximized user experiences (Accessibility, Performance, SEO, Best Practices)
- Participating in weekly or daily scrum meetings for efficient team communication

Frontend Engineer

April 2020 – Present

BarkGrr LLC

- Re-building and co-designing the company's website
- Planning, designing, and building a soon to be released blog
- Implementing modern frameworks and best practices in new projects (React.js, Context API, Gatsby.js, and CSS Grid and Flexbox)
- Creating a re-usable and responsive component library with Storybook
- Setting up and currently managing the company's social media accounts to align posts with upcoming web presence

Volunteer Frontend Engineer & Translator

April 2020 - Present

FightPandemics

- Building new pages from scratch using React.js, styled-components, and Context API
- Diagnosing, fixing, and documenting bugs and User Experience flaws
- Testing and correcting mobile responsiveness
- Attending daily stand up meetings to discuss product development, progress, and issues
- Closely cooperating with an international team of over 450 volunteers with varying backgrounds, first languages, time zones and work locations
- Translating the application to German for future implementation

Au Pair Professional

May 2019 - May 2020

Au Pair in America. Roseville. California

Taking care of three host families' total of 7 children ranging in age from 1 to 14.

- Role model, companion, and additional parent
- Helping to manage the household and schedules
- Encouragement of better understanding of different cultures and improvement of communication, as well as support of the concept of mutual acceptance

Teaching Intern

Jan 2018 - June 2018

German International School of Silicon Valley, Mountain View, California

Teaching 60+ students in grade 2 and 3 in German as a Second Language, Science and Mathematics.

- 100% of students passed the PISA exam
- Successfully organized performances, field trips, learning environments, and afternoon activities

Youth Lead and Dance Teacher

Feb 2014 – May 2019

Various Sports Clubs and Schools

Leading 4 dance divisions and teaching dance and rhythm skills to students aged between 4 and 16.

- Creating training schedules, recruiting and supporting instructors, ordering and creating costumes and advertisements, planning field trips, managing all social media accounts
- Accomplishments include numerous successful dance events and performances, three professional dance and management licenses, as well as a bronze medal for success in promoting the TSV Dagersheim.

EDUCATION

University of California at Davis

Mar 2020

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp

• Graduated top of the class with an A+ grade average

University of Education in Weingarten, Germany

Sep 2019

B.A. in Elementary Education (with focus on Mathematics and Foreign Languages)

- Student President of the English Department
- Active Member of the Math Department